# **Max Lewis**

Aspiring Software Engineer looking to make a difference by creating impact.

Lockport, Illinois, US | +1 (815) 708-4410 | mlew3223@gmail.com

<a href="https://github.com/mslew">https://github.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://maximuslewis.com/mslew">https://github.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://maximuslewis.com/mslew">https://maximuslewis.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://maximuslewis.com/mslew">https://maximuslewis.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://maximuslewis.com/mslew">https://maximuslewis.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://maximuslewis.com/mslew">https://maximuslewis.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://mslew.com/mslew">https://mslew.com/mslew</a> | <a href="https://mslew.com

# **Computer Science Graduate**

I am a recent computer science graduate with substantial hands-on experience with Python, Java, and JavaScript. Perceptive problem solver with an innate ability to learn quickly and apply previous experience with original solutions to solve problems.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Lewis University, August 2019 - May 2023

GPA: 3.82/4.0 (magna cum laude)

- Dean's List: all four years.
- Outstanding Student Employee of the ECaMS Department for the 2022-2023 school year.
- Dr. Stephany Schlachter Excellence in Undergraduate Scholarship Award Finalist.

#### **PROJECTS**

QuizMaster, Spring 2023

(https://github.com/QuizMasterInc/QuizMaster) | Software Systems Capstone Project at Lewis University

- Designed, as part of an Agile Scrum team, a comprehensive quizzing application to keep users' minds sharp on various topics.
- Redesigned and modernized the front-end application from HTML/CSS/JavaScript to React and Tailwind CSS optimizing the user experience.
- Onboarded and mentored Juniors to develop new features and take over maintenance ensuring project continuity.
- Technologies: React, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, Google Firebase, Google Cloud Functions.

# In Theaters, Spring 2022

(https://github.com/mslew/in-theaters) | Mobile Application Development Final Project

- Built an Android application for users to see new movies in theaters that week.
- Designed the application to display information about the movie, resulting in an experience that allows users to browse any new movies and gauge their self-interest.
- Integrated Google services for ticket purchases, providing a holistic movie experience.
- Technologies: Android Studio, Java, IMDb API.

# An ABM of *Clostridioides difficile* in Healthcare Settings, Summer 2022 – 2023 | Mathematics Research Project

- Headed a team for the development of an agentbased model that tracks infections of Clostridioides difficile.
- Forthcoming publication in the Journal of Mathematical Biology, 2024.
- Technologies: NetLogo.

#### **SKILLS**

# **Programming Languages**

- Proficient: Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, NetLogo.
- Working knowledge: Go, PHP, Assembly.

### **Technologies**

React, Node.js, Express.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap 5, Sass, Svelte, Microsoft Azure, Google Firebase.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Will County School District 92 | Building Custodian August 2018 - Present | Lockport, IL

- Maintained building cleanliness per district standards for an assigned 8 classrooms.
- Collaborated with 25+ staff members to establish well-running classes and school events.

## Lewis University | ECaMS Tutor

August 2022 - May 2023 | Romeoville, IL

- Advised 30+ students in Computer Science and Mathematics.
- Collaborated with 6+ professors and 7 tutors to better aid students.

### **AWARDS AND ACCOLADES**

MAA Mathfest, 2022 | Janet L. Andersen Award for Undergraduate Research & The Annual Meeting of the Illinois Section of the MAA, 2023 | Outstanding Undergraduate Research

- Recognized for creating an advanced Agent-Based model to monitor Clostridioides difficile infections in a hospital setting.
- Technologies: NetLogo.